<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on News @ machinelearning.sg</title>
    <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on News @ machinelearning.sg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://news.machinelearning.sg/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OCR (Optical Character Recognition) from Images with Transformers</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/ocr_from_images_with_transformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/ocr_from_images_with_transformers/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to automatically recognise text (OCR) from images of handwritten and printed text using transformer encoder-decoder models.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singlish Text to Speech with Malaya Speech</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/singlish_text_to_speech_with_malaya_speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/singlish_text_to_speech_with_malaya_speech/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to generate spoken singlish audio from text automatically using a pipeline of a Malaya Speech model and applying speech enhancement.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anime Image Super Resolution with PyTorch and Waifu2x</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/anime_super_resolution_with_pytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/anime_super_resolution_with_pytorch/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to upscale anime images by 2x using Waifu2x and CARN V2 super resolution models.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough. 
Continue on if you prefer reading the code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text to Speech with Tacotron2 and WaveGlow</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/text_to_speech_with_tacotron2_and_waveglow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 18:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/text_to_speech_with_tacotron2_and_waveglow/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to generate spoken audio from text automatically using a pipeline of Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s Tacotron2 and WaveGlow models and applying speech enhancement.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text to Speech with Silero</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/text_to_speech_with_silero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/text_to_speech_with_silero/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to generate spoken audio from text automatically using the enterprise-grade SileroTTS model and applying speech enhancement.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Detection with YOLOv5: Detecting People in Images</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/object_detection_with_yolov5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/object_detection_with_yolov5/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to detect people in photos automatically using the ultra-fast You-Only-Look-Once (YOLOv5) model.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough. 
Continue on if you prefer reading the code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Automated Manga Translation with AI</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/fully_automated_manga_translation_with_ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 15:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/fully_automated_manga_translation_with_ai/</guid>
      <description>A recent paper by Japanese researchers shows how they built a system to fully automate the process of translating manga from Japanese to English. Given a manga page, the system translates and replaces the original Japanese text with English and formats it nicely on the page.
 Contextual Information from Manga Images One of the novel innovations of this recent paper titled &amp;ldquo;Towards Fully Automated Manga Translation&amp;rdquo; by Japanese researchers Ryota Hinami et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biology Named Entity Recognition with BioBERT</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/biology_named_entity_recognition_with_biobert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/biology_named_entity_recognition_with_biobert/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to train a BioBERT model for named entity recognition (NER), extracting diseases and chemical on the BioCreative V CDR task corpus. Our model is #3-ranked and within 0.6 percentage points of the state-of-the-art.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI 2020 Roundup: Talent in Demand, GNNs are Hot and a New Macbook M1 for AI</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/ai_2020_roundup_talent_in_demand_gnns_are_hot_new_macbook_m1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/ai_2020_roundup_talent_in_demand_gnns_are_hot_new_macbook_m1/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 of our roundup featuring the latest and greatest AI advancements and directions from 2020. We cover the global shortage of AI talent, Graph Neural Networks being the hotest research area and a new Macbook for machine learning.
 AI Talent in Shortage, in High Demand byt not Pandemic Proof As companies around the world started to embrace AI in 2017 to 2019 and aggressively hire AI talent, demand outstripped supply from universities and institutions of higher learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI 2020 Roundup: AlphaFold, Tennis and Causality</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/ai_2020_roundup_alphafold_tennis_causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/ai_2020_roundup_alphafold_tennis_causality/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 of our roundup featuring the latest and greatest AI advancements and directions from 2020. Today we cover AlphaFold&amp;rsquo;s biology breakthrough, controllable tennis videos and causality touted as the next step for AI.
 AlphaFold&amp;rsquo;s Winning Protein-structure Prediction Competition CASP By a Mile is AI&amp;rsquo;s Biggest Breakthrough this Year AlphaFold2, an AI program developed by DeepMind, completely blew away the competition in a protein-structure prediction competition, CASP, so much so, the co-founder of the competition has commented that &amp;ldquo;in some sense&amp;rdquo; the 50-year old problem, is solved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Profile Pics: Remove Image Background with DeepLabV3</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/beautiful_profile_pics_remove_background_image_with_deeplabv3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/beautiful_profile_pics_remove_background_image_with_deeplabv3/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to remove backgrounds from photos automatically with DeepLabV3-ResNet101 to create that killer professional photo for your next LinkedIn profile picture.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Named Entity Recognition with BERT in Mandarin</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/named_entity_recognition_with_bert_in_mandarin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/named_entity_recognition_with_bert_in_mandarin/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to train a state-of-the-art model with BERT for named entity recognition (NER) in mandarin, 中文命名实体识别. Our model beats the state-of-the-art by 0.7 percentage points.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Named Entity Recognition on Weibo in Mandarin</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/named_entity_recognition_on_weibo_in_mandarin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/named_entity_recognition_on_weibo_in_mandarin/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to train a state-of-the-art model with flair and BERT for named entity recognition (NER) in mandarin, 中文命名实体识别, on a Weibo dataset. Our model beats the state-of-the-art by 20+ percentage points.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis in Mandarin with XLNet</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/sentiment_analysis_in_mandarin_with_xlnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/sentiment_analysis_in_mandarin_with_xlnet/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to train a state-of-the-art model for sentiment analysis on mandarin food delivery reviews using the XLNet architecture. We will use Google Colab&amp;rsquo;s free Jupyter Notebook in the cloud.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train a Named Entity Recognition (NER) Model Using FLAIR</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/train_a_named_entity_recognition_model_using_flair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/train_a_named_entity_recognition_model_using_flair/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to train a state-of-the-art model for named entity recognition (NER), the task of identifying persons, organizations and locations from a piece of text.
 Practical Machine Learning - Learn Step-by-Step to Train a Model A great way to learn is by going step-by-step through the process of training and evaluating the model.
Hit the Open in Colab button below to launch a Jupyter Notebook in the cloud with a step-by-step walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis on Movie Reviews with XLNet</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/sentiment_analysis_on_movie_reviews_with_xlnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/sentiment_analysis_on_movie_reviews_with_xlnet/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to train a sentiment analysis model to classify polarity of IMDB movie reviews with XLNet using a free Jupyter Notebook in the cloud.
 The IMDB Movie Reviews Dataset and XLNet The Internet Movie Database (IMDb) movie reviews dataset is a very well-established benchmark (since 2011) for sentiment analysis performance. It&amp;rsquo;s probably the first large-ish (50,000 train+test), balanced sentiment analysis dataset, making it a very nice dataset for benchmarking on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Train a State-of-the-Art Model for Sarcasm Detection</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/learn_to_train_a_state_of_the_art_model_for_sarcasm_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/learn_to_train_a_state_of_the_art_model_for_sarcasm_detection/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr A step-by-step tutorial to train a state-of-the-art model to detect sarcasm 🙄 from tweets with a free Jupyter Notebook in the cloud.
 Sooo Impressive Sarcasm Detection Model on Tweets Recently Venture Beat published (and Communications of the ACM referenced)
a news article titled &amp;ldquo;AI researchers made a sarcasm detection model and it’s sooo impressive&amp;rdquo; which detailed how researchers from China had come up with a &amp;ldquo;sarcasm detection AI&amp;rdquo; that &amp;ldquo;achieved state-of-the-art performance on a dataset drawn from Twitter&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free GPUs for Machine Learning: Google Colab vs Paperspace Gradient</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/google_colab_vs_paperspace_gradient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/google_colab_vs_paperspace_gradient/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Google Colab and Paperspace Gradient both provide Jupyter notebooks with free GPUs in the cloud to code, train and test your ML models. Which is the better option? In this article we compare them. Our final answer is to use both depending on your current ML workloads and requirements.
 What is Google Colab and what is Paperspace Gradient? If we had to pick one particular tool that makes ML easier for everyone, it would be cloud Jupyter notebooks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Computer Vision Code Repositories from Singapore</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_10_computer_vision_code_repositories_from_singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_10_computer_vision_code_repositories_from_singapore/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr We feature 10 of the top Computer Vision (CV) code repositories from Singapore. These include popular implementations of YOLO3, EfficientDet, DeepLab, FaceBoxes and other models ranging from activity recognition to eye tracking.
The ranking is decided based on the total Github stars of the repositories.
 10. Dual Path Networks   Architecture of DPNs. Retrieved from Github.   This repository contains the code and trained models of Dual Path Networks which won the 1st place in Object Localization Task in ILSVRC 2017, and was a Top 3 team with on all competition tasks (Team: NUS-Qihoo_DPNs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Natural Language Processing Code Repositories from Singapore</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_10_natural_language_processing_code_repositories_from_singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_10_natural_language_processing_code_repositories_from_singapore/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr We feature 10 of the top Natural Language Processing (NLP) code repositories on Github from Singapore. The ranking is decided based on the total stars (stargazer count) of the repositories.
 10. A Multilayer Convolutional Encoder-Decoder Neural Network for Grammatical Error Correction   Architecture of the multilayer convolutional model with seven encoder and seven decoder layers. Retrieved from the official paper.   Code and model files for the paper: &amp;ldquo;A Multilayer Convolutional Encoder-Decoder Neural Network for Grammatical Error Correction&amp;rdquo; (Published at AAAI-18).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Machine Learning Code Repositories from Singapore</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_5_machine_learning_code_repositories_from_singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_5_machine_learning_code_repositories_from_singapore/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr We feature 5 of the top machine learning code repositories on Github from Singapore. The Top 5 is made up of popular implementations of state-of-the-art Computer Vision (CV) and Natural Language Processing (NLP) models and even a high-frequency trading project. The ranking is decided based on the total stars (stargazer count) of the repositories.
 5. PyTorch Implementation of EfficientDet   Architecture of EfficientDet including a weighted bi-directional feature pyramid network (BiFPN).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS2020 - Singapore&#39;s Entries at the Top Machine Learning Conference This Year</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/neurips2020_singapores_entries_at_the_top_machine_learning_conference_this_year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/neurips2020_singapores_entries_at_the_top_machine_learning_conference_this_year/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr NeurIPS is the largest and argubably the most prestigious machine learning research conference internationally. We look at the 44 accepted publications from singapore-based authors in this 2020 edition of the conference, which is happening live this week (6 - 12 Dec 2020).
 What is NeurIPS? NeurIPS is the Conference and Workshop on Neural Information Processing Systems (abbreviated as NeurIPS and formerly NIPS). It is the largest conference in Artificial Intelligence with a specific focus on machine learning and neuroscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AlphaFold2 - 10 Things You Should Know About Biology&#39;s ImageNet Moment</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/alphafold2_10_things_you_want_to_know_about_biologys_imagenet_moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 17:01:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/alphafold2_10_things_you_want_to_know_about_biologys_imagenet_moment/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr AlphaFold2, an AI program developed by DeepMind, completely blew away the competition in a protein-structure prediction competition, CASP, so much so, the co-founder of the competition has commented that &amp;ldquo;in some sense&amp;rdquo; the 50-year old problem, is solved.
 1. What is protein folding? A protein&amp;rsquo;s function is determined by its structure, its 3D shape. The process, protein folding, is how a protein chain acquires this 3D shape and structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
