<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on News @ machinelearning.sg</title>
    <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on News @ machinelearning.sg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://news.machinelearning.sg/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Computer Vision Code Repositories from Singapore</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_10_computer_vision_code_repositories_from_singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_10_computer_vision_code_repositories_from_singapore/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr We feature 10 of the top Computer Vision (CV) code repositories from Singapore. These include popular implementations of YOLO3, EfficientDet, DeepLab, FaceBoxes and other models ranging from activity recognition to eye tracking.
The ranking is decided based on the total Github stars of the repositories.
 10. Dual Path Networks   Architecture of DPNs. Retrieved from Github.   This repository contains the code and trained models of Dual Path Networks which won the 1st place in Object Localization Task in ILSVRC 2017, and was a Top 3 team with on all competition tasks (Team: NUS-Qihoo_DPNs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Natural Language Processing Code Repositories from Singapore</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_10_natural_language_processing_code_repositories_from_singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_10_natural_language_processing_code_repositories_from_singapore/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr We feature 10 of the top Natural Language Processing (NLP) code repositories on Github from Singapore. The ranking is decided based on the total stars (stargazer count) of the repositories.
 10. A Multilayer Convolutional Encoder-Decoder Neural Network for Grammatical Error Correction   Architecture of the multilayer convolutional model with seven encoder and seven decoder layers. Retrieved from the official paper.   Code and model files for the paper: &amp;ldquo;A Multilayer Convolutional Encoder-Decoder Neural Network for Grammatical Error Correction&amp;rdquo; (Published at AAAI-18).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Machine Learning Code Repositories from Singapore</title>
      <link>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_5_machine_learning_code_repositories_from_singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.machinelearning.sg/posts/top_5_machine_learning_code_repositories_from_singapore/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr We feature 5 of the top machine learning code repositories on Github from Singapore. The Top 5 is made up of popular implementations of state-of-the-art Computer Vision (CV) and Natural Language Processing (NLP) models and even a high-frequency trading project. The ranking is decided based on the total stars (stargazer count) of the repositories.
 5. PyTorch Implementation of EfficientDet   Architecture of EfficientDet including a weighted bi-directional feature pyramid network (BiFPN).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
